The Boys are back in town... and they have competition.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel is a comedy,
family, animation film directed by Betty Thomas.
Pop sensations Alvin, Simon and Theodore end up in the care of
Dave Seville's twenty-something nephew Toby.
The boys must put aside music super stardom to return to school, and are tasked with saving the
school's music program by winning the $25,000 prize in a battle of the bands.
But the Chipmunks unexpectedly meet their match in three singing chipmunks
known as The Chipettes - Brittany, Eleanor and Jeanette.
Romantic and musical sparks are ignited when the
Chipmunks and Chipettes square off.
Toby, played by Zachary Levi.
Ian, played by David Cross.
Dave, played by Jason Lee.
Alvin (voice), played by Justin Long.
Simon (voice), played by Matthew Gray Gubler.
Theodore (voice), played by Jesse McCartney.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel is a 2009 American live-action animated jukebox musical comedy
film directed by Betty Thomas and written by Jon Vitti, Jonathan Aibel and Glenn Berger.
It is based on Alvin and the Chipmunks and fictional girl group The Chipettes.
It is the second in the live-action Alvin and the Chipmunks film series.
The film stars Zachary Levi, David Cross and Jason Lee.
Justin Long, Matthew Gray Gubler and Jesse McCartney return to voice the Chipmunks,
while Christina Applegate, Amy Poehler and Anna Faris voice new characters.
The film sees the Chipmunks entering high school under
the care of Dave Seville's cousin, Toby.
Meanwhile, Ian Hawke recruits the Chipettes to restore his career.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: The Squeakquel was released in the United
States on December 23, 2009, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$443 million against a $70–75 million budget.
It was followed by two sequels, Chipwrecked in 2011, and The Road Chip in 2015.
The film explores themes of chipmunk, aftercreditsstinger,
duringcreditsstinger, woman director, live action and animation.
The tone is lighthearted.